# CHUN. WANG

San Francisco Bay Area | 571-315-0540 | chun.wang@appdynamics.com | chunw.github.io

# **SUMMARY**

Software professional with a good eye for design and a passion for making beautiful, enjoyable and smooth user experiences. Experienced in all areas of the software product lifecycle: designing, prototyping, developing, maintaining, and automating end-to-end tests for products of shippable quality.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

General - Java / Python / C++
Web - JavaScript (AngularJS, jQuery, TypeScript, D3.js) / HTML5 / CSS3 / Sketch 3 (UX Design)
Data - SQL / Hadoop / MongoDB / R / Machine Learning / Statistics
Mobile - Mobile web / Android

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Software Engineer II (UI), AppDynamics

San Francisco, CA, 2014 - Present

Designing and developing complex yet performant AngularJS-based web application UI that provides rich interactive data visualizations to help users get deep insight from a wealth of data. Implementing new features and optimizing existing ones, including reusable UI components shared with other products. Working closely with a team including product management, visual designers, and backend engineers to ensure products are shipped quickly and with high quality. Mentoring junior developers with their work.

Software Engineer & Research Intern, Center for Open Science

Charlottesville, VA, 2013-2014

Created interactive data visualization tools that presented user contributions and suggested collaboration possibilities within the Open Science Framework. Conducted social research on the incentive structure for online Open Science communities.

Software Engineer Intern, Curiosity Media

Arlington, VA, 2013

Created delightful web app features for SpanishDict.com, e.g. playing audios/videos in slow motion, recording/recognizing user voices and providing feedback on pronunciation, to help users learn the language with multimedia. Crafted the marketing site (for both desktop and mobile devices) for the company's flagship Spanish-learning app, Fluencia. Developed the internal JavaScript library to track client data which led to UX improvements. Conversion rate raised to 40% on desktop and 22% on mobile devices, from 13% and 5% respectively.

Researcher, Clemson University

Clemson, SC, 2012

Researched cutting-edge machine learning algorithms for complex pattern recognition. Implemented a system capable of interpreting clinical EEG data intelligently and visualizing the results in web browser in realtime at  $\sim$ 4,400 signals/sec.

Research Assistant, Virginia Tech

Participated in two research projects at the Center for Human-Computer Interaction. Wrote MATLAB programs to experiment with statistical models that detected anormalies in 3D scanner data. Applied innovative narrative analysis techniques on interview scripts with emergency room nurses for advancement in healthcare human factors.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Virginia (B.S.'14)

Major: Computer Science; Minor: Applied Math; 3.95/4.00 Major GPA; 3.91/4.00 Cum GPA; Graduated with highest distinction

# **CERTIFICATION**

Interaction Design Specialization, UC San Diego on Coursera (2014)

Post-Baccalaureate Certificate in Visual Arts, UC Berkeley Extension at San Francisco (2015 - Present)